这是二零二四年普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意回答。
听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
sounds interesting. I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three
months ago. I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kind of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages, you know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
that sounds great!
I really need to practice my French.
Okay, well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始，请看听力部分第一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话，
每段对话后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完。
每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间。
看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容。
你将有。
五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间。
David, forget about Mark.
His aunt is in town, so he can't go with us today.
Oh, what a pity.
It's the last day of the art show.
How may I help you?
I bought a desk and asked for it to be to my house this Friday.
Yes? What's the problem?
I need to have it delivered this Saturday.
Next, please. Oh, hi.
I missed my 9 o train to Bedford.
Do I have to buy another ticket?
No. The next train leaves at a quarter to 10 at Platform 11.
Thank you. Thank Honey, have you checked today's weather forecast?
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面五段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有。
几个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间
阅读各个小题，每小题
五秒。
中。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七。
七，两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
Yes, it's cold and wet.
There is a warning for strong winds up to a hundred kilometers per hour.
What are we going to do then?
Nothing much. Just stay indoors.
There is a risk of falling trees and power lines.
Right. And the low temperatures could bring snow to the forest area.
I hope it's over quickly.
Well, it won't get better until late Wednesday.
Anyway, I have to move the car away from the trees.
Yeah, you cannot be too careful.
Yes, it's cold and wet.
There is a warning for strong winds up to a hundred kilometers per hour.
What are we going to do then?
Nothing much. Just stay indoors.
There is a risk of falling trees and power lines.
Right. And the low temperatures could bring snow to the forest area.
I hope it's over quickly.
Well, it won't get better until late Wednesday.
Anyway, I have to move the car away from the trees.
Yeah, you cannot be too careful.
听下面一段。
对话，回答第八至第十
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Hello, Dave. This is Kathy from sunny California.
Hi, Kathy. You finally called.
How was the move?
All settled in?
Sorry I hadn't called sooner, but it's been a busy month.
We're slowly getting things set up in our new home.
Yeah, I understand.
How are Jeff and the children?
Jeff is doing well with his new job.
Tom has made many new friends here and has a lot to do.
Fiona is fine, though she misses her
By the way, thank you for looking in on my mother from time to time.
I call her every week, but it isn't the same as seeing her.
No problem. Betty and I are friends now.
How is the weather there?
It's nice and warm.
And we are able to spend some time every week on the beach with the children.
That's great. Hello, Dave.
This is Kathy from sunny California.
Hi, Kathy. You finally called.
How was the move?
All settled in?
Sorry I hadn't called sooner, but it's been a busy month.
We're slowly getting things set up in our new home.
Yeah, I understand.
are Jeff and the children?
Jeff is doing well with his new job.
Tom has made many new friends here and has a lot to do.
Fiona is fine, though she misses her grandma.
By the way, thank you for looking in on my mother from time to time.
I call her every week, but it isn't the same as seeing her.
No problem. Betty and I are friends now.
How is the weather there?
It's nice and warm.
And we are able to spend some time every week on the beach with the children.
That's great. Thank you.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一。
至第十三三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Jack, how did you get to school when you were in primary school?
I lived close to my school, so I walked every day.
Why? Well, I remember that when we were kids, we often walked, a bike, or caught the
bus to school.
Few of us were dropped off at the school gate by our parents.
I see what you mean.
These days, you can see traffic jams around schools at drop -off and pick -up times.
But it's hard to blame the parents.
They have good reasons for driving their kids to school, mostly to do with safety
and convenience. You have a point there, but it could also mean children are missing
out on much -needed exercise and other life skills.
Some parents are just being overprotective, with their children learning nothing but
living in fear of everything.
Some parents I see what you mean.
days, you can see traffic jams around schools at drop -off and pick -up times.
But it's hard to blame the parents.
They have good reasons for driving their kids to school, mostly to do with safety
and convenience. You have a point there, but it could also mean children are missing
out on much -needed exercise and other life skills.
Some parents are just being overprotective, with their children learning nothing but
living in fear of everything.
Studies have found that children who spend more time outside tend to be healthier,
better adjusted, and better at dealing with stress.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至第十七
四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
So, Marie, your kitchen garden looks excellent.
What made you turn to social media to record your vegetable growing?
So, your excellent.
What you turn to to your vegetable growing?
As time went by, other gardeners and like -minded people began to follow my
progress, too. I know you grow lots of fruit on your land.
Which would you recommend to beginners as the best to grow?
Strawberries would be a good choice.
They produce a of fruit in their first season.
That's cool. Well, do you have plans to try new or any particular crops next year?
Next season, I will be adding some pear trees to the fruit area.
I will be adding more herbs which I can use in the kitchen.
And, after a couple of years of failure, I will try growing carrots again.
What advice would you offer someone thinking of doing kitchen gardening?
Have a plan of what you want your kitchen garden to look like.
Don't be too discouraged if things don't go according to plan.
Learn from your mistakes and move on.
There's always next season.
So, Marie, your kitchen garden looks excellent.
What made you turn to social media to record your vegetable growing?
Initially, I used the online platform as a diary, something to look back on, giving
me a sense of achievement and keeping me motivated and moving forward.
As time went by, other gardeners and like -minded people began to follow my progress
too. I know you grow lots of fruit on your land.
Which would you recommend to beginners as the best to grow?
Strawberries would be a good choice.
They produce a of fruit in their first season.
That's cool. Well, do you have plans to try new or any particular crops next year?
Next season, I will be adding some pear trees to the fruit area.
I will be adding more herbs which I can use in the kitchen.
And, after a couple of years of failure, I will try growing carrots again.
What advice would you offer someone thinking of doing kitchen gardening?
Have a plan of what you want your kitchen garden to look like.
Don't be too discouraged if things don't go according to plan.
Learn from your mistakes and move on.
There is always next season.
听下面一段独白，回答第十八至第二十
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Welcome to Meet the Author.
Well, many readers of Sports Times turn to last page of their magazine first in
order to read Jacob Johnson's weekly article under the title, Life of Johnson.
The articles, along with his novels and essay collections, have earned Johnson the
reputation as one of the funniest humans on the planet.
Johnson began writing about sports as a second -year student at the University of
Colorado, covering high school volleyball games for his hometown newspaper.
After graduating in 1981, he moved on to work at the Denver Weekly for two years and
the Los Angeles Post for two more years before landing at Sports Times.
He has been voted National Sportswriter of the Year 11 times.
So now, let's welcome the funny man with serious talent,
Jacob Johnson. Welcome to Meet the Author.
Well, many readers of Sports Times turn to last page of their magazine first in
order to read Jacob Johnson's weekly article under the title, Life of Johnson.
The articles, along with his novels and essay collections, have earned Johnson the
reputation as one of the funniest humans on the planet.
Johnson began writing about sports as a second -year student at the University of
Colorado, covering high school volleyball games for his hometown newspaper.
After graduating in 1981, he moved on to work at the Denver Weekly for two years and
the Los Angeles Post for two more years before landing at Sports Times.
He has been voted National Sportswriter of the Year 11 times.
So now, let's welcome the funny man with serious talent, Jacob Johnson.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间将试卷上的答案
转涂到答题卡上。
听力部分到此结束。